All right. Right. Can you guys hear us
now?
>> Please put a one in the chat if you can
hear us.
Testing. One, two, three. Testing,
testing. Put a one in the chat if you
can hear us.
>> Of course, Satan's playing games.
Ah,
>> yay. A one. You can hear us. More ones.
Hallelujah. All right. Praise God.
>> Excellent. Excellent.
>> Yes. All I was saying was welcome.
>> That's all.
>> Welcome to You didn't miss anything.
>> Yeah. Welcome to Depending on what part
of the world or country. our country,
world country, part of America you're
in. It's a cold Sunday evening, but we
are glad and happy to be here with you.
Thank you for joining us. Sorry for
being a little bit late. Thank you for
your patience, and we are excited to
continue this topic. I was just sharing
too, you're on, this is a Power of the
Lamb live event. So, if you have never
subscribed or liked uh anything from uh
Power of the Lamb, please subscribe and
like uh this um this link that you're
on. and then share it with someone that
you think will be interested in the
topic that we are talking about this
evening. So again, welcome.
>> Yeah, we know that it's that it is
Sunday night. As we said, we typically
do these on Friday nights. Um
this uh this particular presentation
um is a part two.
>> Yeah. from uh
>> welcome
>> part two from what we did last uh well
two weeks ago now.
>> Two weeks ago.
>> Two weeks.
>> Um if you have not seen
um if you haven't seen
>> part one of this series. Yeah. Um
>> can you hear me better now?
I hope I'm being picked up on my mic and
not Ivor's mic. And that could
[clears throat and cough] be the issue
now. I'm on. So, I should be
>> Yeah.
So, worst case scenario, we might just
share this headpiece
>> or um I can go back to my
>> reg. Yeah. Actually, that mic isn't even
connected.
>> Okay.
>> Well, you're the most important person
that they hear.
>> Yeah. So, uh last night, I'm sorry, two
weeks ago, we did a a study, part one of
the 10 horn study. Um, and if you
haven't seen it, I'd strongly encourage
you to go back and watch it because in
this presentation tonight,
>> um, I'm not going to be, uh, so much,
um,
>> Takara says she can hear me fine.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> So, we're not going to be so much going
over information that we did that we
went over uh, two weeks ago. Um,
>> yeah, you'll just have to go back and
watch it. We're doing part two. We don't
want you guys to be late to work
tomorrow. We don't want you tired for
work. So, we're going to
>> and we're going to try to keep this at
an hour and a half.
>> So, I think
>> we'll see what happens.
>> Well, I'm going to be the timekeeper and
and try to do that.
>> We'll see what happens.
>> I don't want to be tired at work
tomorrow. [laughter]
>> Yeah. Yeah. We'll see what happens.
>> I think my first Anyway. All right. So,
>> time keeper.
>> Yeah. We are going to go ahead, guys,
and uh we're going to pray.
>> We're going to pray. Uh we're going to
jump in and um get ready you guys
because this is going to be some really
mind-blowing stuff. Um
and uh I'm super excited
>> just going over the the presentation and
you know putting some finishing touches
on it. Um I think it's going to help us
to understand where we are
>> right now and why we are here right now.
Uh, so let's pray. Um, again, share, let
people know the presentation is on. Tell
them to tune in. Yes.
>> And, uh, we're going to get into the
word of God tonight. So, Atante, I'm
going to ask if you'd be willing to pray
for us.
>> Yes, I will. And Takara, you're right.
This is more important. She said this is
more important than work.
>> Amen. [laughter] Amen.
>> Amen. All right. Please bow your heads
with me as we pray. Heavenly Father,
Lord, we thank you for this opportunity.
Um we just thank you for all of those
who are here live with us and all of
those who will [clears throat] watch
after um we are done and we'll rewatch
this this very important program. We
just ask that your Holy Spirit would uh
join us at this time as we go through
this Bible study together. We ask these
things in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. Okay guys, so tonight's
presentation is the story of the T horns
part two, but with a specific emphasis
on the why behind the Sunday law and we
are still Wow. Um, okay. Yeah, we had to
create a new link. So, I'm wondering
um if you could uh someone can copy the
link. this link and let those who are
waiting on the other link know that it's
going on over here.
Yeah, if there's at least 100 people
waiting on that other link,
uh they they they need to they need to
know. In fact, um Atante, I'm going to
put you on the spot. Uh
>> oh, guys, I'm being put on the spot.
>> Just ask you to see if you can remember
>> if I can remember
>> um what we talked about. if you could
give a very brief
>> Oh, wow. You're asking me to do the
recap. Wow.
>> Yeah. What? Let me ask you this. What
What jumped out to you as you were going
through?
>> Okay. Um I talked about Yeah, I've
talked about this during um at at church
during our Sabbath school time. But what
was um from the part one that what stood
out to me is the spirit of the ten horns
meaning every event like the same I
think I've said this that um Satan was
not creative he just basically
ran the same play if you will throughout
every single nation um and you know and
power that um represents um the t horns
And so it was um it was just one the
greed and power and using um
>> Christian
>> Christian or yeah Christian
>> the what what characterist what happens
when you merge
>> clay and iron
>> together
>> together and the end result is what we
saw
>> in those 10 horns.
>> Yes. And in every single power um that
was taken over. And I just thought like
and then and that's exactly what he's
still trying to do
>> uh with the final one and um
>> I guess he believes he was well he was
successful in trying to do that and he's
going to try to do that again. But so
good as you can God is so good that when
you continue to study uh Daniel you know
that Michael will stand up and
>> gonna put an end to all of this. Yeah.
Um but um it's it was definitely a
powerful study and I can just see how it
impacts us today especially and where we
are in history um and what he's trying
to do um here in America for sure what
he's currently trying to do and he has
just been planting seeds
>> um of that spirit and bringing um the
church and state trying to bring church
and state together for a while. But he I
have to say that he is patiently doing
all of these things and weaving them in
so it can come to a big crescendo of
what he's really wanting.
>> Yeah. And a lot of people don't see it
and that's why we're talking about this
tonight.
>> Exactly.
>> Um so
um
we are I've just shared the link.
>> Yay. Um,
so we are uh we're going to go ahead
guys and we're going to start with uh a
very familiar
uh text. Um
let me go ahead and share my screen
and uh all right there we go.
>> Like some of our people welcome to those
who are just joining us and who are on
the the old link. um because a new link
had to be created. But we're happy that
you are here. Welcome to the part two of
the study of um the T horns.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So guys, you haven't missed
anything. We're starting now. We just
>> we waited for you.
>> Yeah. So we are just getting ready to to
jump in now. So let's go ahead and begin
with Daniel 2:41.
The Bible says here, "And whereas you
saw the feet of toes and part of
potter's clay and part of iron,
the kingdom shall be divided, but there
shall be in it of the strength of the
iron. For as much as you saw the iron
mixed with myy clay, and as the toes of
feet were part of iron and part of clay,
so the kingdom shall be partly strong
and partly broken. And whereas thou
sawst iron mixed with miry clay, they
shall mingle them themselves with the
seed of men, but they shall not cleave
one to another, even as iron is not
mixed with clay. So um
guys, we are we're going to actually
start off with a bombshell
um today tonight. Um, when we read in
Daniel chapter 2 about these toes of
iron and clay, the Bible tells us that
they're going to attempt to mix together
or mingle together. Um, but ultimately
they will not succeed.
So, [clears throat] what I want you to
understand,
>> just want to do a clarification. I don't
know if somebody thought I said Satan
wasn't created. I said he he's not
creative.
>> He's running the same place. So, no,
Satan definitely was created. Yeah.
>> Okay. Go ahead.
>> Okay. So,
um the the goal of the T horns and we
talk about it all the time, how
Charlemagne tried to unite the kingdom
and how Hitler tried to bring all the
all the kings together and all these
different conquerors tried to unite the
kingdom uh but that it would not
succeed. So the first thing I want to
suggest to you
uh as we are doing this 10 horn studies
is if you remember from our last study
>> the 10th horn
now remember we talked about how
typically when we study the subject we
focus on the papacy we focus on the
three horns that were uprooted and then
we kind of leave it there right we don't
even pay attention to the other horns we
just kind of mention them in passing oh
oh this horn will now represent Spain
and this horn now represents you Germany
and etc. Well, what we what what I want
you to understand is that that last
horn, if you don't know who that last
horn is yet, we're not going to say it
yet because it's part of our buildup. If
you haven't heard this study before, but
that last horn will be the final horn to
attempt
>> a global
kingdom,
and it will nearly succeed. We know this
because the Bible tells us that all the
world is going to be united
>> worshiping the beast.
So in other words, what the other nine
horns could not do
getting political power strong enough to
to bring the whole Roman Empire at that
time and now the whole world together.
the last horn
will come very close to accomplishing
that. So close that Michael stands up
and says, "No, that's not going to
happen."
>> Cuz I'm just I'm I'm meshing back to the
basic back to the basics and this study
right here.
>> Um,
>> so you're saying that it's the tenth
horn, but
it's not. I mean, it's really I don't
want to say it's not. I mean, it's it's
happening during their reign when
they're doing what they're doing, but
it's really a a false miracle.
>> It will be in Yeah. in the time of that
tenth horn
>> is where that whirlwind, the whole
appearing of Satan, all those things are
going to happen. But
>> they will have set it up.
>> Yes. The key horn,
>> the key horn
>> will be that last horn, that final horn.
if you will, outside of the papacy. So
again, if you've never heard this
before, you're going to have to go back
and watch part one of the 10 horns. But
>> there is something that I that that
we have probably many of us have missed
and I know I missed it up until
yesterday.
>> Well, you've missed it. I know I missed
it because
>> Yeah. [laughter]
So the the Bible says that they would
mingle themselves with the seed of men.
And for whatever reason, as I was
putting, you know, completing my study
last night, for whatever reason,
>> the Holy Spirit just impressed upon me
that phrase, mingled themselves with the
seed of men. And I'm like, wait a
minute, wait a minute.
>> Where have I seen that concept before?
Let's go back to the screen, y'all.
Okay.
>> Do you remember in the book of Genesis
[clears throat]
chapter 6, the Bible says, "And it came
to pass when men began to multiply on
the face of the earth, and daughters
were born unto them, that the sons of
God saw the daughters of men, that they
were fair, and they took them wives of
which they all chose."
um this
verse
in Genesis chapter 6,
you know, the many people in the
Christian world think we're talking
about angels that were mingling with,
you know, uh marrying women.
>> That's what I've always thought that
that
>> no
>> meant. Okay. Okay. Go ahead. that that's
the Christian world thinks that
>> right
>> we understand that the sons of God
represents the offspring of Seth and the
sons of men represent the offspring of
Cain.
>> Okay.
>> So
the reason why the flood comes
>> is that the holy line is mingling with
the corrupt line.
>> Right? Okay,
>> I need y'all to catch that.
>> This is the first place in the Bible
where God condemns the mingling
together. And in fact, um, if we read
John Gil's commentary on this, John Gill
says this. He says, "This is to be
understood of the posterity of Seth who
from the thing who from the times of
Enos when they began to when then when
then began to or when they began to be
called by the name of the Lord in
Genesis 4:25 had the title of the sons
of God in distinction from the children
of men. These claimed the privilege of
divine adoption and professed to be born
of God and partakers of his grace and
pretended to worship him according to
his will so far as revealed to them and
to fear and to serve and glorify him. So
John Gil is pointing out something that
we as a church already understand.
>> Ellen White says this for some time the
two classes remain separate. The race of
Cain spreading from their first
settlement dispersed over the plains and
valleys where the children of Seth had
dwelt. The latter in order to escape the
contaminate the contaminating influence
withdrew to the mountains and there
maintain the worship of God in its
purity. But in the lapse of time they
ventured to mingle with the inhabitants
of the valley. The sons of God
saw the daughters of men that they were
fair.
>> Wait, wait, let me read on. The children
of Seth displeased the Lord by
intermaring with them. Many of the
worshippers of God were begal to sin by
the allurements constantly before them,
and they lost their holy character.
mingling. Everybody put that word in the
chat for me, please. Mingling with the
depraved, they became like them. The
restrictions of the seventh commandment
were disregarded, and they took them
wise of which they all chose. The
children of Seth went in the way of
Cain. They fixed their minds on worldly
posterity, prosperity, and enjoyment,
and neglected the commandments of the
Lord. Sin spread abroad in the earth.
Patriarchs and Prophets, page 81. So
what we understand here beloved is that
the reason
for the destruction of the world,
>> y'all put a one in the chat if you're if
you're following the connection.
The reason for the destruction of the
world in the days of Noah
was because the holy line of Seth
mingled with the corrupt and worldly
line of Cain.
>> And it is this mingling
>> that brought about the destruction.
>> Now, I hope y'all are sitting down. Are
y'all sitting down? Make sure you're
sitting down before I read this next
verse. Okay? Because this verse, this
next verse is suddenly going to explode
in your mind. And man, oh man, oh man,
check this out, y'all. Y'all ready?
>> Yes.
>> In the book of Matthew 24:37,
Jesus says this, "But as the days of
Noah were, so also shall the coming of
the Son of Man be. For as in the days
that were before the flood, they were
eating and drinking,
>> marrying,
>> marrying and giving in marriage.
Pause for a second, y'all.
I have to see your your faces by faith.
marrying and giving in marriage.
Understand
that in Daniel 2
>> when when God is is showing the prophecy
of the iron and clay mingling, we have
already established that the clay would
have is a representation of God's
professed people while the iron is a
representation of the world of of Rome
of the of the political element. And
what's happening in Daniel chapter 2 is
that they are marrying and giving in
marriage.
>> Okay, I think I'm
>> I know what y'all are thinking right
now.
>> I thought Jesus was saying
>> that marrying in the last days is going
to be bad.
>> That's a thing that we shouldn't be
doing in the last days.
>> Beloved,
>> mingling. mingling
>> the seed of they shall mingle with the
seed of men. In other words, what we're
seeing here is that the
>> what brought about the first destruction
of the world through water was marrying
and giving in marriage.
>> Right?
>> What will bring about the final
destruction of the world by fire is
marrying and giving in marriage. exactly
what Daniel chapter 2 is pointing us to.
In other words, Daniel 2 is telling us
is revealing to us as as we've already
seen
>> that it is this mingling together
of that which is supposed to be
political. I mean that which is supposed
to be religious mingling with the
worldly element of politics that will
ultimately bring about the stone cut out
without hands that destroys the image on
the feet. If y'all are with me so far,
just give me a give me a three in the
chat to let me know. We're just This is
just the setup.
>> This is just a setup.
Okay, so now we get it. We're look what
we're what we're looking for is this
concept of church marrying state.
Anywhere that we see church marrying
state,
>> anywhere that we see that, we're going
to understand
this is the result of what Daniel
chapter 2 is talking about. Mhm.
>> We should not be on board
with any attempt or any movement
>> that is seeking to marry and give in
marriage. Are y'all following what I'm
saying?
>> So,
so with that in mind, I want to read
another statement to you. We're going to
go back to the screen.
>> I'm going to read another statement to
you. And uh this is from uh let's see
here. This is from the great controversy
page 296. Listen to this.
>> The regulation. She's talking about the
early colonies of America. Now, okay.
>> And I want you to listen carefully to
what she says. And we might we could
just stop right here. Stop the entire
study right here and just lock in on
this slide.
The regulation adopted by the early
colonists of permitting only members of
the church to vote or to hold office in
the civil government led to most
pernicious results. This measure had
been accepted as a means of preserving
the purity of the state but it resulted
in the corruption of the church.
A profession of religion being the
condition of suffrage and office holding
many actuated solely by motives of
worldly policy
united with the church without a change
of heart. Thus the churches came to
consist to a considerable extent of
unconverted persons and even in the
ministry where those who were not only
were those who not only held errors of
doctrine but who were ignorant of the
renewing power of the Holy Spirit.
>> Thus again was demonstrated the evil
results
so often witnessed in the history of the
church. Listen to this y'all. from the
days of Constantine
to the present of attempting to build up
the church by the aid of the state
>> of appealing to the secular power in
support of the gospel of him who
declared my kingdom is not of this
world. John 18:36,
"The union of church with state, be the
degree ever so slight, while it might
appear to bring the world nearer to the
church, does in reality bring the church
nearer to the world."
>> Okay,
we need to build on this on this slide
for a moment.
>> Great controversy, page 296.
What we just read was a warning.
The warning basically states, listen,
the pre-erequisite
of attempting to have people in office
that are only Christian.
>> In other words, if I vote for you, you
must be Christian. And everybody I vote
for must be Christian. and we should
only have Christian leadership. She says
that very thing while meant
to p to to
preserve the state
>> brought about the exact opposite
results.
>> Y'all put a five in the chat if you
understand the the principle there.
The colonies literally made it law that
you could not serve in office if you
were not a Christian.
>> If you were not a Christian, if you
didn't believe as we believe, then you
can't serve in office because you or
anyone who votes for someone who is like
you is going to bring society down. And
I want you to note their main concern
was about society versus the word of
God.
>> Right?
>> So they wanted everyone to be this thing
for the sake of the society.
>> That was the first and primary thing for
the for the state of America to be what
it what it should be. We've got to make
sure
that everybody's following God. Not we
should we want everybody to follow God
so that they can be saved. No, this
nation
>> but to make America good
>> is is a godly nation and therefore all
who serve in this nation and all who
vote in this nation should vote on the
side of God.
I just had a thought because what you
just said that that spirit and that
wording has um been said in many
different um
arenas. not quite like that like you
have to be you know Christian and how
they were saying that but but that
spirit of that
>> um and I was just thinking it's almost
like where Satan wanted to take the
place of God and um almost like like
America is heaven and to make America
like and and he be king
>> and rule.
>> This is what I want you to see here. The
spirit of that whole concept is what she
tries to use the political world to do.
>> That's right. That's that's the basis
we're gonna be building on.
>> I wanted to I want you to read this
again. Okay. We're not going to read the
whole thing. Just listen again. The
regulation adopted by the early
colonists of permitting only members of
the church to vote or to hold office in
the civil government led to the most led
to most pernicious
results.
>> The measure had been accepted as a means
of preserving the purity of the state.
It's almost as if the state was idolized
above the individual.
And then what she does is she connects
this concept back to Constantine.
>> So guess where we're going to go, y'all?
We're going to go back to Constantine.
>> Remember in in Daniel chapter 2, we have
Babylon and then Meersia and then Greece
and then Rome.
>> And then Rome is a kingdom that breaks
down. But remember before Rome uh uh uh
begins to to to to break down, in other
words, before the rise of these 10 horns
and the little horn,
it is Constantine that paves the way
>> for what the rest of the horns
and the little horn is going to do.
Y'all put a eight in the chat if you
understand the concept. Understand what
I just said. Constantine is the one
through his conversion
to Christianity. His conversion to
Christianity
>> uh is the one that is going to set the
foundation
that which Ellen White says is exactly
what we're seeing today
>> and what we saw in the early stages of
America.
>> Okay. So, let's let's read a little bit
about Constantine. And um I'm going to
put this back up on the screen.
This is from Advent Review and Herald um
volume 69, August 9th, 1892. And it's a
little bit lengthy, but I I need y'all
to listen carefully and really lock in
and don't miss this. Okay, so here's
what it says. In the beginning of the
4th century, and by the way, I'm not
sure if this is Uriah Smith or at Jones.
I'm not sure which one, but I'm going to
read it anyway. In the beginning of the
4th century, there was in the Roman
Empire a powerful ecclesiastical
organization, the leaders and managers
of which were only anxious to assert the
government as a kind of sovereignty for
themselves.
It was the hope of every bishop in the
empire to make politics a branch of
theology. It was the aim of Constantine
to make theology a branch of politics.
In an intrigue therefore with
Constantine, they succeeded in bartering
to him their influence and power in
theology for his in politics. So, do you
see what's going on here?
They're describing a marrying and giving
in marriage between Constantine and the
bishops in his day. Mhm.
>> And what I want you to see and lock in
on here, because remember this is
leading to Sunday law.
>> Okay? What I want you to lock in on here
is this.
There was an expediency.
>> In other words,
these bishops
were really after political power. Mhm.
>> And Constantine after political power
knew that if he had these bishops on his
side, he could attain the power that he
wanted.
So when you see these conversions
happening within the T horns,
>> it's not really y'all, it's not really
about Jesus as much as it was about
political power and influence. Everybody
put a five in the chat if you understand
what I'm saying.
>> Five. I mean, that's
>> this is a story of all ten horns.
>> All ten horns.
>> It It was not
They weren't like, "Man, Jesus really
made a difference in my life and I'm
going to serve him now."
>> It was all politically motivated
>> to to access political power. Please
keep in mind everything that we're
talking about. I need you to lock in
mind to lock in that while we're talking
about the past, we're also talking about
the very present where we are right now
>> and the future, what is to come,
>> right?
>> Okay. So, we we see here Constantine
and the bishops, it was really a power
play. Let me keep reading. Let me keep
reading. So, as one of the very first
fruits, oh, by the way, let me go back
here.
Okay, here we go. As one of the very
first fruits of this, so this is still
the same source. We're continuing
reading. Constantine was established
uh was established in the rulership of
one half of the Roman Empire jointly
with Lasinius.
He then issued the edict of Milan or
Milan
reversing the persecuting edicts of
Diolesian and granting liberty quoting
now liberty and full freedom to the
Christians to observe their own mode of
worship. Granting likewise to the
Christians and to all the free choice to
follow the mode of worship which they
may wish.
>> So this edict of Milan or Milan
um was issued in 313
>> AD. So remember now something is going
to come along in 321 AD.
>> We understand that to be the Sunday law,
but we're not there yet. We're at we're
in Mil. We're at the edict of Milin 313
AD. And in 313 313 AD, this edict was
basically a reversal of all the
persecution, all the persecuting uh um
laws and legislation that were made
towards a Christian church. Mhm.
>> This is considered, listen carefully
y'all, this is considered the very first
religious
liberty edict
>> that involved Christians.
The very first.
>> The very first. Okay.
>> Okay. Does that make sense? How many of
you love religious liberty? Put a one in
the chat for religious liberty.
>> We love religious liberty.
>> Amen. Mhm.
>> And look, Constantine grants religious
liberty to all the Christians. And he's
like, "Okay, y'all, not only the
Christians, but even those who wanted to
worship whatever they wanted to
worship."
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Let's [clears throat] see what the
article goes on to say.
So it goes on to say
that each may have the privilege to
select and to worship whatever divinity
he pleases and commanding that the
churches and the church property that
had been confiscated by dio by dialesian
should be restored to the whole body of
Christians and to each uh conventicular
respectively.
So he's saying everything that was taken
away from the Christians during this
persecution is to be given back to the
Christians. Right? I mean that sounds
like man that's that's great. Wow. Look
at that. That
>> that sounds good.
>> Now I want you to note what what the
article goes on to say.
The rule had been long let me see here.
Here we go. The rule had been long
established that all who did not agree
with the bishops of the Catholic Church
were necessarily heretics and not
Christians at all. It was now claimed by
the Catholic Church that therefore none
such were entitled to any benefit from
the edict restoring property to the
Christians. In other words, the Catholic
Church disputed the right of any others
than Catholic to receive property or
money under the edict of Milin by
disputing their right to the title of
Christians. All right. Do you see Do you
get what just happened? Do you see what
I do? You do I need to reexlain what
what I just read?
>> Really?
>> Let me explain it.
>> Explain it.
>> When this edict is passed, say when
Constantine says, "Hey, all Christians,
you know, they get their stuff back,
>> right?" The Catholic Church comes up
comes in and says, "Wait a minute.
>> Whoever isn't a Catholic is not really a
Christian.
>> They are heretics." And therefore, the
religious liberty is not really for
them.
>> It's for us.
>> They are just heretics.
>> They took a religious liberty issue.
Listen to me y'all.
They took a religious liberty issue.
and began to twist it for their own
benefit.
>> All right,
let's keep reading.
And by this issue, the Catholic Church
forced an imperial decision as to who
were Christians. And under the
circumstances, by the power and
influence which she held and by what she
had already done in behalf of
Constantine, it in behalf of
Constantine, it was a foregone
conclusion if not the concerted plan
that this decision would be in favor of
the Catholic Church. Consequently,
Constantine's edict to the proposal
contained these words. Now watch this.
It is our will that when thou shalt
receive this epistle, if any of those
things belonging to the Catholic Church
of the Christians in the several cities
or other places are now possessed either
by the by um
>> decursions,
>> either by decurons or any other, these
thou shalt cause immediately to be
restored to their churches, since we
have previously determined that
whatsoever these same churches before
possessed should be restored to them.
Here's what he goes on to say. That was
not what it said at all. It was not the
Catholic Church to which the edict said
the property was to be restored. It was
to Christians. It was to Christians
alone, to the whole body of Christians.
But mark you, just as quickly as that
was said, the Catholic Church made a
turn upon that word Christian and forced
a decision by the imperial authority as
to who were the Christians intended.
And as she had given him her influence
in politics, he did not dare say
otherwise because if he should, she
should swing her influence over to
Leinius or some other one and he would
become and he would become emperor. She
had political power in her hands and she
used it. Thus in less than 11 years from
the issue of the Edica of my land the
Catholic Church stood in full and
exclusive possession of the authority of
the empire both in the rights of
property and the right to worship under
the profession of Christianity and with
a specific and direct commission to use
that power and authority to compel the
submission of heretics. Thus was made
the papacy,
>> the beast of Revelation 13:1-10, and all
that ever came in its career from that
day to this has been but the natural and
inevitable outgrowth of the power and
prerogatives
which were then possessed and claimed by
the Catholic Church. And it all came
from the edict of Milan of Milin
bestowing governmental favors upon the
Christians. No man can fairly deny that
in the edict of Milin and the religial
political intrigue that lay behind it
there was contained the whole papacy. No
man can successfully deny that the edict
of Milan, though appearing innocent
enough on its face, contain the whole
papacy or the things that followed in
the 10 years up to 3:23
which we have sketched where anything
else than the leg the than the logical
and inevitable development of the evil
that lay wrapped up in that.
All this came out of that edict and
nothing came out of it that was not in
it. Nothing could come out of it that
was not in it. All right. So, let's
pause right there.
Here's what I want y'all to understand.
The Catholic Church, let me just say
this. The church of that day
>> used religious liberty. I don't know if
y'all are listening to me. Mhm.
>> They used religious liberty and twisted
it.
>> Yes.
>> To make it applicable
to themselves.
>> Right.
>> And it is this that then lays the
foundation for what happens in 321 AD
when Constantine passes
a Sunday law. M
>> come on now. Let's go back to the
screen.
>> Great controversy. Page 5, page 53.
>> In the early part of the 4th century,
the emperor Constantine issued a decree
making Sunday a public festival
throughout the Roman Empire. The day of
the sun was reverenced by his pagan
subjects and was honored by Christians.
It was the emperor's policy to unite the
conflicting interests of heathenism and
Christianity. He was urged to do this by
the bishops of the church who inspired
by ambition, not inspired by worship,
>> not inspired by we've got to make Rome
great, not inspired. They were inspired
by ambition and thirst for power.
perceived that if the same day was
observed by both Christians and the
heathen, it would promote the nominal
acceptance of Christianity by pagans and
thus advance the power and glory of the
church. So, watch this, y'all.
>> Wow. Wow. Wow.
>> Watch this. Watch this.
>> On the church side,
>> they were like, "Look, if we can just
get a bunch of heathen in, we don't even
have to baptize them. If we can just put
up a a symbol that says, "Hey, this
means you're Christian.
>> Then we get more money. We get more
power. Constantine. If you do this, you
unite your kingdom and you get political
power. You're not re reigning over a
divided kingdom. And what you have
happening is is prostitution.
>> Mercy.
>> What you have happening is the sons of
God mingling with the daughters of men.
>> Mercy.
>> And now watch this you guys. The Sunday
law is not an attempt to convert
anybody.
>> It's an attempt
>> for it's an attempt to to acquire
political power.
>> It's an attempt, y'all listen to me,
>> to gain
political power and prowess.
to unite the kingdom
>> under one rulership
so that all the power-hungry bishops and
all the power- hungry political leaders
are scratching each other's back. And
now it makes sense because the the
Sunday law was really a symbol of Rome's
greatness.
>> Y'all y'all y'all not I don't know if
y'all caught that just now. The Sunday
law would become the symbol of Rome's
greatness.
>> Wasn't really about worship.
>> It wasn't really about we've got to
honor the Lord. It was motivated by
ambition and greed. Mhm.
>> Y'all put a five in the chat if this
makes sense. Put a five in the chat if
you are following and understanding
the context now the backdrop. Remember
we're leading up, beloved, to our time,
but we're starting we're starting back
>> where Ellen White says, "Here's where it
all started." Right?
>> Where prophecy says, "Here's where it
all started.
So then then we have the council the
Nyian council
>> 3:25 AD.
>> So you got you have uh the the edict of
Milin
>> you got the Sunday law 321 and then you
have the the nyan council
>> mil I just I'm mil.
All right. So,
uh, the Council of Nika,
how Constantine shaped Christianity and
the medieval world. This is that actual
document I'm reading from. Let me quote
it to you.
>> Constantine faced a profound political
challenge. Having recently emerged
victorious from civil wars to become
sole emperor, he recognized that a
divided Christian, a divided
Christianity
could undermine his vision for imperial
unity.
His solution was unprecedented.
summoning
summoning an ecumenical council where
bishops could debate and resolve their
differences under imperial opices. Most
significantly, Christianity offered
Constantine a new source of legitimacy.
By allying with the church, he could
claim divine sanction for his rule
independent of traditional Roman
institutions like the Senate. This
theology of empire would become central
to medieval kingship. In other words,
Constantine caused this council of
>> Nika to to settle this dispute between
Aryanism,
>> right? God, you know, there's no trinity
versus the trinity. And a lot of us get
caught up in the well, which position
was right. And what you need to
understand, you know, some people say,
well, you know, whatever position the
Catholic Church took, that's the wrong
position. Constantine
sided with with trinitarianism first
but then gave his support to the Aryans.
>> So this is not an issue of well which
one is right. There are both remember
both of these systems are are in the t
horns
>> right? So
Constantine
is basically maneuvering
calls council because of political
expediency. He's like, "We can't have
this going on because this is going to
cause headaches for me in my political
kingdom." Mhm.
>> Once again, what I'm trying to
demonstrate to you is that the real
motivating factor behind all of this is
politics.
It's politics.
It really wasn't about Jesus.
>> No,
>> it really wasn't about It was about who
wielded power, who had power, and which
church was going to be favored or which
belief system was going to be favored by
the government.
And Satan wants to use the government to
bring worship back to him by the masses.
>> That's right.
>> That's his whole point.
>> And he just feels like if I can get
every
government power to come together in
this whole world, that's how I'm going
to get the masses to worship with me.
>> That's right.
>> With a little miracle.
>> Yep.
>> Daniel 7. Yeah. Daniel 7:24. I want you
to notice what this says. Daniel 7:24.
And the 10 horns out of this kingdom are
10 what? What are they everyone?
>> Kings.
>> There are 10 kings that shall arise.
Not 10 religious entities,
>> right?
>> Not 10 spiritual people,
>> Not 10 priests,
10 kings.
In other words,
Daniel 7:24 is telling us, listen y'all,
no matter what goes on here in these 10
in these 10 powers, remember there are
10 kings. They are political.
>> Yeah,
>> that's the bottom line. These are 10
kings. And it literally says, watch
this.
>> We are really silly to to to just rush
over the 10 horns because there's so
>> Yes.
>> much here. like this kind of brings it
all together to be honest.
>> Yep.
>> And that like
>> it's just rushed over or just avoided
all together.
>> Look at this. And another shall arise
after them. Hold on a second. Another
what?
Another what? So if the T horns are
kings
>> and then it says, "And another shall
rise after them." Then another what?
>> Another king.
The little horn, you guys, is nothing
but another king
doing what the other kings had done.
Using religion
>> to access mental power over the people.
>> Mercy.
>> Are y'all following what I'm saying?
10 kings and then another little horn
which is a king himself. This is all
political. So what I want you to
understand now is there's a reason why
God is so against the mingling of the
sons of God with the daughters of men.
Because what happens is that the sons of
God get corrupted by the daughters of
men. M
>> the clay gets corrupted by iron. In
fact, it's miry clay.
>> Mhm.
>> Dirty clay,
>> filthy clay.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. How are we doing so far?
>> Good.
>> Let's read a little bit more. Let's read
a little bit more. So, here's another
document. is called conversion politics,
motivations behind Clovis's baptism and
the religious and political
repercussions. So now we're talking
about Clovis. So remember after the fall
of Rome, Clovis is the first horn,
the kingdom of the Franks, he's the
first horn to convert to Catholicism.
And I want you to listen to what this
says about Clovis. While the miracle
inter while the while the miraculous
intervention of the Christian God may
have convinced him that is Clovis of
this deity's existence and power had the
benefits of a public conversion not
outweigh outweighed the cost his baptism
into the faith might not have occurred
at least publicly and his alliance with
the church might not have existed.
Therefore, his ultimate decision to
become a member of the Catholic Church
was significant because it led to the
creation of an association between the
Catholic Church and the French monarchy
that exists until the French Revolution
in 1789.
You guys, this is not a prophetical uh
article I'm reading from. This is just a
historical and and the name of the
article is conversion politics. Just
stop right there.
>> Wow. Conversion
politics. Do you tell tell me about that
term? You guys put it in the chat. Tell
me about the significance of that term.
Conversion politics.
Meaning
>> trying to use polit politics to convert.
>> It's conver it's converting
for the for the political benefit.
>> Yeah. Not Yeah. Okay. Not the heart.
>> It's converting for political benefit.
for political expediency.
>> Nothing to do with Jesus.
>> Mhm.
>> When you're converting for political
expediency, when you're all of a sudden
Christian for political h if I become a
if I say I'm a Christian, I'll get
thousands of votes no matter how corrupt
I may be.
>> Yeah.
>> And of course, I'm referring to
Constantine, right? So, um, y'all get
the idea. It's absolute. I want you to
understand how transactional
>> conversion politics is. All I've got to
do
>> is quote a Bible verse. Say I'm a
believer. Say I'm a Christian. And
>> all that
>> the Christian, this is what happened
with the Franks. This is what happened
with with the Sway. This is what
happened with all these 10 kings, y'all.
>> Can I say this is what's so sad because
the
the higherups or the leaders of that
time or you know whatever time now and
then uh were being corrupt and just
wanted power.
>> That's right. the people,
there's people who had genuine hearts
that felt like, okay, well,
in their understanding, they love God,
and if the leader is going to claim God,
well, then that's the the banner I need
to be under. And so, they follow the
leader that's that's using God's name.
>> Yep.
And the reason they most often did it is
because they didn't have a Bible in
front of I was just going to say
>> they were ignorant and the leaders took
advantage of their ignorance.
>> And you know what's crazy? I believe
that today even though we have Bibles it
everywhere,
>> there's still so much ignorance when we
have ignorance.
>> We act like we don't have Bibles.
>> And people just This is not anything
new, you guys. Like that's kind of what
I'm trying to get across, right?
>> This is not something new.
And as we're tracing this through
history, we we have to come to the place
we're like, "Wait a minute. What am I
watching here?"
>> I mean, I thought it was innocent at
first. I thought it was godly at first,
but they must have thought the same
thing when Clovis converted.
>> They must have thought the same thing
when Constantine converted. Mhm.
Mhm.
>> Are we falling for the same trick that
God is trying to reveal to us that the
the enemy was pulling off in all these
ten horns.
>> So, let's go back to the screen and I'm
going to show you. Okay. Um, so here's
what we have, you guys. Here's what we
have. So if you look at all 10 horns,
you will see that there was political
expediency for all their conversions.
All their conversions.
>> There was political reason behind it.
These range from, you know, surviving in
enemy territory to getting aid from the
from the Catholic Church, uh to getting
aid from other political other uh uh uh
tribes who had made associations, you
know, saying, "Hey, we're like there
were so many political maneuverings for
all of these so-called conversions from
the Burgundians and the Franks and the
Lumbards and the Alamani and the Herili
and the Anglo-Saxons. All of these,
beloved, and some of these, we're going
to see some of the all of these, even
down to, which we're going to get to in
a moment. But remember Anglo-Saxon
Britain, the reason that Ang the
Anglo-Saxons become Protestants,
>> King Henry, tell me that wasn't
political.
>> Yeah.
>> We're going to set up our own church.
just because I cannot remarry the way
that I want to because we're going to
just set up our own church. We're going
to have our own headquarters and we're
going to bring all the all we're going
to we're going to set up our own kingdom
here.
>> Every conversion, all the 10 horns,
including the three that are uprooted,
their their religion
revolved around political expediency.
>> Political expediency. Okay. How are we
doing so far?
How are we doing so far?
>> Good.
>> Y'all put up sense.
>> Is Is it making sense?
>> Are we following? Remember, we haven't
we haven't gotten to the to the
explosive stuff yet.
>> We're still building up.
>> Wow.
>> So, one in the chat, if you're like,
"Pastor, we're following. This makes
sense.
It's adding up. Now, remember this. So,
this is a little bit of recap from what
we did last week. And I'm not even going
to I'm just going to going to kind of
skip, but you'll remember that in some
of these horns like the suvi and uh the
visog gods. So we're not talking about
Spain and Portugal, right?
>> We're just talking about these two,
Spain and Portugal. We see here that one
of the results of ming of this marrying
and giving in marriage results in
Spain in Portugal
involved in both the doctrine of
discovery
um as well as the inquisition,
right? We talked about that two weeks
ago. In other words, remember the pap
the papacy is now giving these bulls
these decrees. Let me see if I can pull
them up. Yeah, here we go. Let's let's
just let's just put this on the screen.
Um, [clears throat]
Portugal explorers, uh, Nuno Trista and
Antonio, uh, Conclaus
conducted some of the earliest known
Atlantic voyages, capturing Africans and
bringing them to Portugal in 1441. By
1460, Portugal was taking hundreds of
Africans annually, and the trade
expanded as uh, expanded as forts were
built along the West African coast. This
set the structural precedent for what
became the transatlantic slave trade.
Europeans capturing or purchasing
Africans and transporting them across
the ocean for labor. In that sense,
Portugal is widely considered the first
European state to systematically engage
in what became the transatlantic slave
trade. And what set the path for this
was Catholic declarations such as dumb
dem diversus authorized the king of
Portugal to subjugate s uh um sars and
pagans and reduced them to servitude.
The Romanus pontificates pontific
expanded Portugal's right to conquer and
trade in non-Christians non-Christian
lands especially in West Africa.
the Intercatira
issued after Columbus's voyage granting
Spain rights to to lands west of the
demarcation line and to spread
Christianity there.
All of these decrees are now giving
these horns in the name of Jesus.
>> Remember now in the name of Jesus to
conquer other people and to conquer
other lands. of course, for the purpose
of evangelism.
You see how that works? We're just
trying to win their souls, but we're
going to go take their territory, their
money, and all it was all political.
Like, that's the point that we want to
that I want to because we're leading up
to something, you guys.
If if if we cannot be fooled by the
facade of Christianity in those days,
>> then we will be in a better mind frame
to not be confused by the facade of
Christianity in these days.
>> That's what we're trying to draw a
straight line and connect the dots so
that when we get to these days, there's
no, "Oh, you're just making this up. Oh,
you're just being political." No, no,
no, no, no. I I need you to understand
that this has been going on and the
Bible prophesied it. And to deny it is
to deny prophecy,
>> right?
>> We talked about Germany, the Alamani.
So, we've been looking at all the ten
horns and watching what, you know, what
was their significant
uh contribution demonstration to show
here's what happens when you mix iron
and clay. when the sons of God mingle
with the daughters of men. And in the
Alamani, which is not which would grow
to become Germany, we see Hitler.
>> Mhm.
>> We see this idea of racial superiority
while using Christianity
>> as a shield to do do so.
>> This is God ordained.
When Satan hijacks
Christianity,
he's doing like a double-edged sword.
Like he's doing the real dirty work that
he wants to do and also just making
other people, you know, not want to
serve the true God.
>> Absolutely.
>> Because it's so disgusting.
>> Absolutely. this and with this um na
calling it Christianity and taking over
territory and to get power
>> I mean it's just yeah
>> it's just utilizing
>> the name Christianity to do all the evil
things
>> absolutely
>> that he wants to do and it's so horrible
>> and it's so horrible
>> and the down slavery and
>> and I think one of the worst things
about it for our day
>> is that there are many of us who have
the Bible I'm not even talking about the
Christians out there in the world who
are not reading the Bible,
>> right?
>> There are those of us who are in the
remnant church, who have our Bibles and
the Spirit of Prophecy and are still
down with G with marrying and giving in
marriage,
which is a very scary thing.
Ju just don't see it. Just gung-ho like,
yes, this is the side that we're on.
Yes, these are the these are this is the
philosophy that we should hold as a
church. We've got to stand for the right
just as they were doing in the days of
Constantine, just as they were doing in
the days of Clovis, just as they did in
in I was talking with someone uh
tonight. I don't know if this number is
accurate, but he brought it up. He said
80% of Adventists in Germany
>> voted for Hitler.
>> You've mentioned you didn't say that.
>> I know it was a lot, but you but if it's
80% and I was shocked. I I did not I did
not know that but that's
yeah
>> that's crazy.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That is very crazy that
Adventist
at that time.
>> Other churches this is not you know
singling out Adventist but I'm just
saying Adventist should not have been in
that number.
>> They should not have been in that
number.
>> We know prophecy. We understand. And yet
some were so blinded by this German
>> Can I say this?
The only way that can happen within
Adventism,
like you say, we know property. We have
property. I mean property, prophecy.
We're the we are the the people of the
book. Only if you
what I'm trying to say is there's
>> when you put nation
over
>> Well, there's that. But the only reason
why you would do that is because you're
kind of just Adventist in name only. You
really don't
>> understand prophecy. You're going to
church. You're saying happy Sabbath.
You're studying the Sabbath school
lesson. That's everybody else is
studying, but not going any deeper than
that.
>> It's just I was baptized. You know what
I'm saying? But I'm not really I'm not
really knowing everything. I'm not
really studying. I'm not really engaging
in all of this. I'm not sharing. I'm not
growing with this knowledge. And so
>> to say that so many people like just
even with Germany were able to do that.
I mean we have a lot of that same
>> not Hitler mindset but just laxidasical
oh this is the Christian thing to do.
And listen, remember a lot of these
people
>> because the masses of Christianity were
following
>> Yeah.
>> Hitler in Germany
>> and they they bought into his
philosophy,
>> right?
>> There was a there was a buying into
Yeah, we are the superior race.
>> I was just going to say and there had to
have been a foundation of racism there.
>> And and remember now
>> he couldn't have entered in without
that.
>> We need to help Hitler because he's
vegetarian,
>> which is silly. And whoa, what an
opportunity for, you know, I mean, yeah,
we know he might have some, but hey,
he's got he's got the health message
down.
>> Mhm.
>> So, let's connect.
>> Let's connect. And you see this this
thing happening.
>> You're connecting. I'm just so you're
being clear and not like people don't
>> I think what you're saying you're
talking about how Adventists gravitated
to Charlie because he kept the Sabbath.
>> This were you going there? Okay. Well, I
don't know. I thought you were going
there because and I'm not comparing
Charlie Kirk to Hitler. I'm just saying
>> them gravitating and saying he kept the
Sabbath. So,
>> when we look at the philosophy,
>> we can support Turning Point USA.
>> Yeah. When we look at the philosophy of
these organizations and we're just like,
well, you know, yeah, they stand for
everything we've just seen, but hey,
they're vegetarian
or hey, they do this like we do.
I mean, praise God, but that's not a
that's not a um
a go-ahehead to say, "All right, well,
we're down with with with everything you
stand for,
>> right?
>> This is what they This is This is
demonstrating, I believe, that when we
see a Christianity that as long as you
hold a certain position, we're just
going to go ahead and back you because
you're obviously on God's side. So all
the other stuff we'll wink at, you know,
yeah, he's killing people, but you know,
we'll wink because he's a vegetarian and
we'll wink because the the church is
behind this, so we're good to go. This
>> this is what prepares people. There is
um there is a just
there is it was uh Bonhaofer
who was you know in Hitler's time put to
death
>> for his attempt to take Hitler's life
but Bonhaer came up with while he was in
jail he wrote something called the
theory of stupidity
>> and it wasn't like a it wasn't like a
>> aka racism
>> right well [laughter] no no what he what
he was talking about
>> stupidity yeah what he saying was, "How
is it that people who are otherwise
intelligent,
>> how could they have just fallen for the
mass hypnosis of Hitler
>> and not say anything and not be like,
"Wait a minute, something's wrong here."
And not be like, "You know what? Hold
on." That
>> Well, I think what I said was correct
then because and that's what I was going
to say earlier, like if the foundation
if he can if what Hitler was able to do
was able to connect to the racist heart,
we're better.
>> That's right. So then so now you're in
this and now the spirit of stupidity or
whatever there it connect that is the
foundation.
>> Yeah. And the basis
>> we're not better than each other. It
don't matter you know in any no one not
one race is better than another.
>> And the basis of the 10 horns is
dominance.
>> Yeah.
>> Dominance. We want to dominate
>> because we're better
>> through Christianity. And for some it
was ra it was hey racially not only are
we better. We're just better racially.
And for others it was just we just want
power.
>> Right.
>> But what I'm saying is in that final
>> but Satan has to connect somewhere.
>> That's right. He's got to connect
somewhere
>> in our in our
>> That's right. And in that final horn,
all of the elements that came in the
previous nine horns. We're going to talk
about this final horn now. All of those
elements will be manifested in the final
iteration which is going to bring the
whole world together.
>> Mingle.
Mhm.
>> We're watching it unfold right now.
>> It's act we're actually seeing this. And
this is not something new. That's what
I'm trying to say. This is not something
new. When we study these 10 horns, we're
like, "Wait a minute. This has been
happening.
>> All the other horns failed
>> in
accomplishing what this last horn is
going to accomplish."
>> So, let's go. Let's go back to the
screen.
We're now going to go to the last horn,
and that is the horn we haven't spoken
about yet, the Anglosaxon
horn. Let's go back to the screen, and
we're we're pulling up to Sunday law.
Okay, so we're we're getting there.
We're getting there. Um the first in, by
the way, this book uh is called Race and
Manifest Destiny, written by Reginald
Horseman. And I'm just going to read
several quotes to you. We we read some
of these two weeks ago. I'm gonna read
them again. And just just listen
carefully. Listen carefully. The first
enthusiastic English interest in
Anglo-Saxon England was a product of the
English Reformation. As early as the
1530s,
the Saxon church was studied to provide
propaganda to justify Henry VII's break
with Rome. Now you guys this is very
interesting because what it's basically
saying is that even within the
Protestant Reformation so listen now
right okay we see this with the Catholic
Church and the horns that are Catholic
>> but even among the horn two of the horns
the the Alamani Germany Martin Luther
and the Anglo-Saxons Britain
>> John Wesley
two of the horns that become Protestant
in nature and become major moving forces
in the Protestant uh in Protestant
history. Two of those horns are going to
eventually demonstrate when the when
King Henry becomes
Protestant,
what has he done? He's simply replaced
the pope with himself.
>> And now everybody in England is
Protestant.
>> It's a law.
which ends up being one of the reasons
why people started leaving England
because of the persecution
that is now being done by Protestants.
Same spirit. Same spirit.
>> But here you have the the the the the
Anglo-Saxon horn now using its
Anglo-Saxon
um
genetics to say, "Hey, genetically we're
better than the Catholics. We're better
than those Europeans. They were of a
different breed. we are from this, we
are Anglo-Saxons and etc. And
Anglo-Saxons are higher and more
intellectual than
the masses that that are making up the
Catholic Church.
>> Okay, so let me go back. Let me go back
to race and manifest destiny and let's
see what else he says. The main object
of the research was to show that the
English church was returning to the
power to the purer practices of the
period before 1066. supposed Anglo-Saxon
precedents were used to support the
argument that England had had cleansed
the Roman Catholic Church of the abuses
introduced through centuries through the
centuries by papal power. Now, I want
y'all to catch this because literally
what they're saying is, listen,
>> we're against the Catholic Church
because not because of the necessarily
the false doctrines, but by nature we
were better than them.
Now, I mean, if God inspired the
Protestant Reformation to be based on
this is error and this is truth,
you know, the devil's going to try to
get in there.
>> And he does.
>> He says, "Hey,
let the Protestant Reformation be based
on the fact that you guys are a higher
breed."
>> The Anglo-Saxons were were a conquering
people. We were a people of pride and we
were a people that were, you know, we
ran risks and all these things about the
Anglo-Saxon which glorified
Anglo-Saxonism above everybody else
which is what is now tied in with
Protestantism. Listen to me y'all
because remember it is this Anglo-Saxon
horn
that is going to be the founding bring
about the founding of the United States
of America
>> and Protestantism within the United
States of America.
Let's go back to the screen.
The interest in Anglo-Saxon religious
sources which helped to justify the
break with Rome also eventually helped
overturn the authoran legends which had
dominated medieval accounts of the
origins of the English people. The study
of the Anglo-Saxon institutions provided
justification for English rejection of
papal authority.
And now we get to Revelation 13:1.
>> How y'all doing so far? M
>> Are y'all good?
>> Revelation 13:1. Revelation 13:1. Let me
check again. How are y'all doing? Are
y'all good? Cuz now we're about to get
into into the the meat. And we're about
to tie all these strings together,
>> okay?
>> All these roads together. So watch
Revelation 13:1. The Bible says this,
"And I beheld another beast coming up
out of the earth. He had two horns like
a lamb. and he spake as a dragon. So I
want you to understand now
who is it,
right? I was talking with a friend today
and he was like, "Isn't it interesting
how Spain and Portugal, you know, and
and and and France were all trying to
get a piece of this land to to establish
it as their own, but it ends up that
it's the Anglo-Saxon horn
that gets the whole land. H.
>> So when we read Revelation 13:1,
what we are reading is a continuation of
the Anglo-Saxon horn from Daniel 7,
which is why I call it the 10th horn.
>> Everybody put a one in the chapter.
Y'all understand now? This is the 10th
horn.
>> And it is this horn, the Anglo-Saxon
horn, which forms the United States of
America. Uh uh uh um that is going to be
that power that brings the whole world
together. It is the final iteration of
iron and clay. The final manifestation
of
sons of God
>> mingling with the daughters of men. Mhm.
>> So we can expect then that everything we
saw in the horns previously, we are
going to see in this final horn.
>> Mhm.
>> We're going to see in this final
iteration. This horn is going to connect
with the little horn.
>> This is the horn that's going to bring
all the other horns
to worship.
Bring all the world to worship the first
beast whose deadly wound was healed. So
let's keep reading.
Verse 12.
And he exercised all the power of the
first beast before him, and causeth the
earth, and them that dwell therein to
worship the first beast, whose deadly
wound was healed. And he doeth great
wonders, so that he maketh fire come
down from heaven on the earth in the
sight of men, and deceive them that
dwell on the earth, by the means of
those miracles, which he had power to do
in the sight of the beast, saying to
them that dwell on the earth, that they
should make an image to the beast, which
had the wound by a sword, and did live.
And he had power to give life unto the
image of the beast, that the image of
the beast should both speak and cause
that as many as would not worship the
image of the beast should be killed.
Should be killed.
>> Okay. So,
we have here uh this lamblike beast
>> that rises up out the earth. And it is
not coincidental, you guys.
Let me let me read what Uriah Smith says
here. And I want you to understand how
just non-coincidental
coincidental this is. In light of
everything we've spoken about, Uriah
Smith says this about this beast.
>> Its character, it has two horns like a
lamb. The lamb feature is a fit emblem
of the profession and the early acts of
this government. But it speaks like a
dragon. a fit el emblem of the practice
of this hypocritical nation.
Look at the declaration of independence
and the constitution and then look at
slavery. Look at the religious
intolerance, the corruption, the
oppression existing throughout the land.
A further development may be expected in
the future. Uriah Smith identifies
Revelation 13:11 as America and says the
way that we know it's America is just by
looking at its profession versus his
action.
>> He called it a hypocritical nation.
>> A hypocritical nation. And now he says
we may expect a further development in
the future. In other words, there's
coming something worse in the future,
but look at it now.
Why is he using slavery?
Why is he using racial superiority to
describe this beast?
Why?
>> Because it was just being like all the
other horns and trying to and using
Christianity. That's right. For power
>> to
>> it is the tenth horn.
>> And using Christianity be to be able to
enslave people for power.
for power and money. It's always money.
>> We're trying to evangelize the Indians
>> by killing them.
>> We're trying to evangelize.
>> It's a good thing that we're, you know,
bringing the the the slaves here. We're
trying to evangelize them and teach them
about Jesus,
>> even though the Sabbath was known in in
Africa before.
>> And so, you have all of this going on.
And
>> Uriah Smith says prophetically speaking,
and it's not just Uriah, it was multiple
of our pioneers who are saying, "Yeah,
this beast is Revelation 13:11 is
America." And here's why. It is
Protestantism specifically. And here's
why. Now, why is that significant?
Because what you're going to find is the
same philosophy of the Anglo-Saxons. And
this is not Listen, guys. I'm not
talking about I'm never talking about
all Anglo-Saxons or all uh you know
France or all Suavei. We're talking
about the system,
>> right? We're not talking about
individuals as it were. We're talking
about the the belief system,
>> the the the philosophy.
You can buy into it or you can reject
it. As Christians, we reject every
philosophy that is of the world, whether
it's connected to us culturally or not.
That's what we do. Right. Right? I'm a
Christian first and then whatever else
second. When I am Jamaican first before
I'm a Christian, we're in trouble.
>> When you are American first before
you're a Christian, you're in trouble.
When you are a French person before you
are a Christian, you're in trouble. The
moment we elevate
>> our culture above being a Bible
believer, we are mingling with the sons
of men
>> because that's what they do.
>> That's their pride, their goal, right?
>> That's what they're about.
>> Jesus said, "My kingdom is not of this
world."
>> But I want you to note this. We're going
to go back to the screen and I want you
to see this.
From the Puritans to Thomas Jefferson
and Benjamin Franklin, the early leaders
of the United States were steeped in a
racial ideology of a divinely ordained
Anglosaxon heritage, a romanticized
account of the ancestral and cultural
roots of the inhabitants of England.
They believed they were building a new
nation with a divine purpose, a new
Israel with a two-fold mission, racial
and religious. So, what I want you to
see here, beloved, is that when I'm
telling you that that this idea uh of
the Anglo-Saxons being racially superior
transitioned to Protestantism in America
because it was the Anglo-Saxons that
brought it here
and that America was in essence founded
on this idea.
I'm not making stuff up. Mhm.
>> There was good in America and there was
bad in America. Right? This is not
saying, you know, America as a land is
cor that's that's not what I'm saying.
What I'm saying is that there were there
are negative elements in America and
there were positive elements in America.
Many good people in America that stood
for right throughout every period of
oppression. There were people who were
standing up for what was right, for what
was godly, what was Christian. People in
different churches. It wasn't just
blanket like
>> there were churches supporting this,
>> but there were also churches and church
members who were like, "No, we're not
we're not down with this. This is not
what Jesus is talking about." So
understand what I'm saying. But I'm
saying prophetically speaking, we need
to understand what these ten horns led
to, what this tenth horn is about and
how prophecy foreshadowed it, and how if
we don't pay attention, we will end up
denying prophecy
and actually get caught up just as they
did in the days of Constantine, just as
they did in the day of the Franks, just
as they did in the days of of Hitler's
Germany. You have to
And and and let me say this about even
in our in the music world. I'm just
going to speak to this y'all. We
Christianity has become such a joke
>> that you can make music about the
runiest,
craziest stuff and then just say, "Oh,
I'm a Christian." And people be like,
"Ah, look at that."
>> So you can
>> Christian. I'm not calling any names.
>> No, I know. I was just the most recent
comment where you I don't know if you
were reading the comments. Never mind.
Oh, okay. Well, then you were just
>> your audience is is tracking with you.
They're tracking.
>> Yes. I I'm I'm not here to call
>> Yeah. I wasn't going to call the name. I
just thought you were connecting to the
comment. [laughter]
>> Yep. Yep. Yep. Mhm.
>> We've taken
Christianity has been brought down and
has been dumbed down to a level that it
is just like it was in the days of of of
Constantine's decree.
>> Hey, if we make Sunday the day, then
everybody's Christian.
>> We'll just have heathens just coming
into church. No conversion. But hey,
you're a Christian now, so we're good.
>> Look at how many people Look at how well
we're doing. Lord,
>> you see all these people that are now
coming to church. unconverted, but
they're here.
Okay,
so we're going to go back to the screen
and we're going to keep reading.
Manifest destiny is a term coined in the
1840s to describe the belief that the
expansion of the United States across
the American continent was both
justified and inevitable. The phrase was
first used by newspaper editor John L.
O. Sullivan in 1845 who argued that it
was America's manifest destiny to
overspread the continent allotted by
providence for the development of
liberty and self-government. This
ideology was rooted in American
exceptionalism and the belief in the
superiority of American culture and
institutions. So, we're going to pause
for a second.
I'm going to exit this. In fact,
let me
Stop sharing here.
I'm going to come back to this slide.
Okay, here we go.
Stop share. And I'm going to pull
something else up here.
Okay.
So,
all right.
[clears throat]
So,
let's talk about this for a second.
Let's talk about 1844.
1844.
Okay.
Do y'all remember, and you know, we
already I just gave it away. It's on the
screen.
>> How many of you were aware that Darwin
wrote his the the uh first draft of his
book in 1844?
>> That's when the first draft was
released. I think it was 1842 and then
1844. put a one in the chat if you were
aware that Darwin's book on evolution,
his first draft was in 1844. That's
pretty significant.
>> I've heard you say that before. That's
why I knew.
>> Yeah,
>> it's it's significant because in 1844,
God is also bringing a movement upon the
scene
>> that is supposed to take the three
angels messages into the world.
>> Right
>> now, now remember Darwin's book is going
to do two things. Number one,
it's going to bring doubt in creation.
>> The the Genesis account of creation. Lo
and behold, God has a people who in the
very same year have been given the
message of the seventh day Sabbath which
verifies, which solidifies, which backs
up the creation account. That's number
one.
>> Number two, if I may, number two, let me
Here we go.
Okay.
So here you see uh essay essay part one
draft a this is Darwin's manuscript
1844.
Um, number two, that same book, the full
title [clears throat] of that same book
is called the origin of species
by means of natural selection or the
preservation of favored races in the
struggle for life.
Not only does Darwin's book challenge
creation and our relationship to God,
>> but now it challenges
now it challenges the idea of equality
among the races. Mhm.
>> So that the two commandments, love God
with all your heart, soul, and mind and
then love your neighbor as yourself,
>> are literally being challenged in
Darwin's book.
>> Yeah.
>> Because he's talking about creation and
now he's talking about, hey, one race,
there are some races that are better
than others. M
>> h what are the odds that God is calling
a people who have been called to preach
to every nation, kindred, tongue, and
people
>> about a message of God's creation,
that God is the creator, that the
Sabbath is a sign of his creation, that
the commandments are to be kept, that
we're to love God and love our neighbor
as ourselves. What do you think the odds
are of Darwin's book being written or
the first draft he's working on it right
at the time that God is producing a
message that is designed to bring the
world together with the gospel?
>> Think about that.
>> We go past Darwin, we see that in
America, we've got we got, you know, uh
um racism happening. We've got slavery
going on. Mhm.
>> We then have the Jim Crow era and wa
okay this makes sense because it's the
Anglo-Saxon philosophy.
>> Now remember not all people have bought
into this philosophy but there is an
element of Protestantism
that has connected itself with with that
is looking for political power and has
connected itself with this idea of
racial superiority and and American
exceptionalism.
M
>> remember we're we're getting to the
Sunday law, y'all.
Why will a Sunday law be issued?
>> Mhm.
>> And who will it be issued by?
>> So, [clears throat] let's go back to the
screen and I just want to we're just
tracking here. Okay,
here is a book called the gospel
according to the clan. So, now we have
the clan in the late 1800s and the early
1900s. And as you as you all well know,
what is the clan using as their shield?
It's Christianity.
>> It's Christianity. Not only is it
Christianity, but it is American
exceptionalism. Not only is it American
sex exceptionalism, it is it is an
Anglo-Saxon philosophy.
>> This is what the clan is doing.
>> And the clan is doing their thing and
they're saying, "Hey, this is the
Christian thing to do." They are they
are extremely uh uh concerned about uh
other people and other races in our
community. And in this book in this book
that I just showed you, the the the
gospel according to the clan, I want to
read to you that that destiny included
more than patriotic duty. It also
included uniformity in Protestant
Christianity and white supremacy.
The Anglo-Saxon heritage of the clan and
of America directly resulted in the
greatness of the nation and racial
purity ensured the maintenance and
development of the group mind.
Americanism then was not simply about
democratic government but about but also
about the racial superiority of whites.
Aliens would destroy the group mind as
well as democracy, a cherished American
ideal. So no aliens.
>> We don't want people coming into America
that are not like us.
>> And and in fact,
the book goes on to say, "Aliens and
foreigners were the greatest threat to
the unity of mind, the unity of mind or
Americanism."
And so here you see a picture of the
clan and you know their their log their
their model is America first.
>> Mercy.
>> I hear I hear that all the time now.
>> Yeah. It's America first. And behind
that America first is implicit
>> all kinds
of philosophies
that are designed to show the the spirit
of pride and nationalism and and and
exceptionalism
for only a certain group of people. Mhm.
>> In the book, The Passing of the Great
Race, and we talked about this in
Sabbath school, this past Sabbath
school. In the book, The Passing of the
Great Race, which was written in 1914,
it says in New England, however, whether
by the way, this book, The Passing of
the Great Race, is a book designed was
written to warn about the danger of
America becoming a melting pot. Mhm.
>> It says in New England, however, whether
thou whether through the decline of
Calvinism or the growth of altruism,
there is there appeared early in the
last century a wave of sentimentalism,
which at the time looked upon the cause
of the negro and in so doing apparently
destroyed to a large extent pride and
consciousness of of race in the north.
The agitation over slavery was was in
was enimical to the Nordic race because
it thrust aside all national opposition
to the intrusions of hordes of
immigrants of inferior
racial value and prevented the fixing of
a definite American type such as we
clearly such as was clearly appearing in
the middle of the century. That's page
77.
[clears throat]
Let me read. The Cucas Clan used the
phrase at the organization's peak in the
1920s when racist xenophobic sentiment
was widespread. It formed it informed
many of their members who ran for
political office. The Immigration Act of
1924 sponsored by Washington US
Representative Albert Johnson was a
legislative expression of xenophobia. It
targeted Japanese, Eastern and Southern
European migrants, immigrants by
excluding them on ba basis of ethnicity
and national origin in an effort to
preserve the country's existing ethnic
demographics.
Johnson's leading role in the
immigration restriction bill elicited
strong support from the KKK. What I want
you to understand, beloved, and and you
may be thinking, well, okay, this is
bad, but you know what does it have to
do with, you know, what we're really
this is all part and parcel, yeah,
>> of the 10 horns philosophy,
>> right?
>> It's corrupt Christianity in the name of
Christianity.
>> That Yeah, that tenth horn, the angles,
>> the tenth horn and all the horns before
it.
>> So, so what I want you to see is that
the things that have been happening in
this country are not coincidental. Mhm.
>> Okay. So, just let's just go through and
see all the phases, right, of of this.
>> When the clan is talking about America
first, it's not talking about all of
America.
>> It's talking about white America.
>> Yeah. Yes.
>> That's pretty self-explanatory, but
>> Yep. So, so here you see here's all the
things, right? all the stages of of of
uh racial superiority by a Protestant
element in our country,
>> right? I'm not going to go through all
these in detail. I just want you to see
that this is real. You can trace this.
You can trace this. Now, I want you to
watch this, beloved. Want you to watch
this. The Bible says in Revelation
13:15, he had power to give life unto
the image of the beast, that the image
of the beast should both speak, and
cause that as many as would not worship
the image of the beast should be killed.
>> What is the image of the beast?
What is the image of the beast? I'm
going to ask you guys, just put in the
chat for me. What is the image of the
beast?
[clears throat] Ar say, who is the image
of the beast?
The beast itself is the papacy. It's a
church state entity, right?
>> But the image of the beast, what is
that?
>> The image of the beast is when America
>> sets up
a government based on religious
superiority.
We are the truth. This is the truth.
>> Nobody else is Christian. We are the
Christians. So remember remember back in
Constantine's day
>> when the church was like, "No, no, no.
They're heretics and they're heretics
and they're heretics." It's going to be
that same thing again.
>> If you don't fall in line with our
belief, you are heretics. And guess
who's going to be singled out, you guys?
>> Guess who's going to be singled out as
heretics?
>> You guessed it. those who keep the
commandments of God and have the
testimony of Jesus Christ. We know that.
>> But here's what I want to say to you
guys. The image of the beast, listen to
this now, is Christian
nationalism.
>> What nation?
It happens in the American nation. Mhm.
>> Which means beloved
that the worship of the image
is in essence the worship of the nation.
I need y'all to think about that. I need
y'all to stop for a second and think
about that.
The worship, the image of the beast is
when America forms a type of of system
that reflects the papacy.
>> So to worship the image, the beast or
its image will be in essence to worship
America. Mhm.
>> And now you're beginning to see, wait a
minute, wait a minute. Is this why
the devil is so
busy on making America an
idol
>> for so many Christians?
>> Remember, that's right, Jamie. In Daniel
3, the image of the beast in Daniel 3 is
an image dedicated to Babylon.
>> It is the worship of Babylon.
>> It is the worship of King Nebuchadnezzar
and Babylon. Not in Daniel 2, in Daniel
3. He sets up an entire image and says,
"This image represents my kingdom.
Worship the kingdom."
>> Mercy.
>> Worship the kingdom.
>> Mercy. And so in in Revelation 13 then
what we have happening is basically a
worship of a kingdom.
>> And now we begin we begin we can begin
to see oh
that's why the devil is so busy trying
to make America
>> an idol to so many
>> Christians.
There is this worship.
>> We are to love God and to love one
another, not a nation.
>> We Oh, man.
Listen to this. Let's go back to the
screen, y'all. Let me read. By this
first beast is represented the Roman
church, an ecclesiastical an
ecclesiastical body clothed with civil
power, having authority to punish all
the sinners.
The image of the beast represents
another religious body clothed with
similar power.
>> The formation of this image is the work
that of that beast whose peaceful rise
and mild profession renders it so
striking a symbol of the United States.
Here is to be found an image to the
papacy. When the churches of our land,
uniting upon such points of faith as are
held by them in common, shall influence
the state to enforce their decrees and
sustain their institutions, then
Protestant America will have formed an
image of the Roman hierarchy. Then the
true church will be assailed by
persecution
as were God's ancient people. Almost
every century furnishes examples of what
bigotry and malice can do under a plea
of serving God by protecting the rights
of church and state. Do y'all see this?
>> It's almost as if she's saying you look
at the history of the T horns, the
history of the papacy, you will see that
in every one of them you see the same
thing.
>> And we will see it in the United States
of America. Protestant churches, listen
to this, Protestant churches that have
followed in the steps of Rome by forming
alliance with worldly powers have
manifested a similar desire to restrict
liberty of conscience.
>> In the 17th century, thousands of
non-conformist ministers suffered under
the rule of the Church of England.
Persecution always follows a religion
favorit a religion um
a religious favoritism on the part of
secular governments.
>> You guys listen
alliance with worldly powers
following in the steps of Rome with a
similar desire to restrict religious
liberty. Listen to me you guys.
All this talk, all this talk of the
churches about religious liberty, I need
you to understand it is the same spirit
of back there in the days of
Constantine.
>> Religious liberty. Oh yeah, that's but
let me tell you what religious liberty
really means.
>> It really means this. It's really for
us. Not your liberties, our liberties.
And beloved, that is exactly what we
read will happen in the United States of
America. Not by Marxists,
not by secularists
>> who are like, "Yeah, live as you please.
Let everybody do what they want to do.
Mhm.
>> It is the religious element
>> using religious liberty
>> to really bring about a state in which
the liberty means liberty of conscience
for me
>> and not for thee. Mhm.
>> So,
so [clears throat]
now I'm going to read to you a very
powerful statement from one of our
former uh uh um from a um
one of the founders of our one of the I
should say pioneers of our church.
>> Okay?
>> And I need y'all to listen to this
carefully. Okay? I have several here.
We're almost done, you guys. Let me show
you. Let me just pull this up here.
Okay? Listen. If the nation if from if
the nation
is a moral personality as it is claimed,
it must have a conscience and its
conscience must be must direct the
latter in any matter which with which it
has to do. And this being so, the nation
becomes the individual's god and
nationalism the individual's religion.
This is written in 1897, y'all.
The nation becomes the individual's God.
>> Mercy
>> and nationalism the individual's
religion.
>> The work of the gospel is to make peace
between men and God. And wherever a
heart surrenders to God, the spirit of
militarism and nationalism must go. M
>> I can I can sense that that some of you
may be mad reading this, but I'm not
saying it. I'm just reading.
>> I'm just reading.
>> And now listen to this, y'all. Listen to
this powerful powerful
statement
by WA. Spicer.
Here's what it says. That thought of
Americanism, of nationalism, is
something to reckon with. I am an
American. I'm not ashamed of it, but I
am not proud of it.
>> And that makes all the difference in the
world in being able to help people
outside of America. For you take any man
who is proud of the fact that he is an
American and he has erected a barrier
between himself and every soul who is
not an American.
>> Anybody who has been in a foreign field
has known this fact. difficulties which
perhaps it has taken years to clear away
have been created by those who kept the
national spirit forward.
It is a part of that old paganism of
Rome that caused men to worship the
genius of the empire instead of God.
>> That thing is so drilled into men that
it clings to the natural heart. It was
sometimes taught us in our schools in
the little school histories of the
United States. It was worked into us and
made our hearts thrilled with the
fighting spirit. That same spirit keeps
on thrilling in minds and hearts even
after men have taken up the work of God
and gone out into foreign fields.
The Lord wants to take that spirit out
of our hearts.
>> We are take we are to take up this
message of God in the spirit and power
of Elijah. How did John the Baptist go
forth when he bore the message of the
coming Lord in the spirit and power of
Elijah? We read in the first chapter of
John, there was a man sent from God
whose name was John. He was sent from
God. It makes all the difference in the
world whether a man is sent from God or
whether he is sent from America
>> or from some other land. You find the
spirit of nationalism in all lands.
Wherever you go in every nation, you
will find that some that you will find
that same national conceit and every man
feels like praising and glorifying his
country. Why? simply because it has
produced such a great man as am I. That
is all. It is simply the conceit of the
individual and all the people that
creates the national spirit of rivalry
and self-exaltation
that is at the bottom of nearly every
war that stirs the surface of our earth.
Wow.
>> Wow.
I want y'all to understand the spirit of
idolatry.
>> He goes on to say this, and it could not
be otherwise. When the Jewish church
turned from the close, turned from the
close yet healing message of John and
Jesus, a message which if received would
have restored, they were ready to reject
Christ their king and to say, "We have
no king but Caesar."
And so when the modern church rejects
God's healing message of reproof and
warning, she will turn to the world and
the state and under the guise of
Christian citizenship, patriotism, or
Americanism will denounce as traitors
those who reveal by the true word of God
the the true nature of the church and
state dogmas, the children of
fornication.
M
>> you guys
that is one of the most powerful
statements
>> that I have read
>> that is relevant to what
>> is going on in our country today.
>> Yeah. and especially in our church
>> today,
>> I [clears throat] praise God that of
every
in every one of those 10 horns, God has
had people that have stood up and said,
"No, I'm not going the way of this
culture,
>> right?" In the Anglo-Saxon horn, in the
Frankish horn, in the Swayar horn, in
every one of these systems, God has had
people who were genuinely his and and
said, "Nah,
>> not going for that."
>> Doing that.
>> Just like in the very last uh iteration
of this prophecy, Babylon. God has a
people that are in Babylon now who will
who will come out when they see these
things you and I are talking about. Wow.
>> Mhm.
>> When they un Wait a minute. What?
>> This is what we've been doing.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
>> you know what? I just want to say that
just really understanding this through
what the T horns represented and what in
the spirit that's here now. Like we have
such um a work to do.
>> Yeah.
>> We have such a work to do. We have no
time to be uh complacent or not sharing
>> the true gospel and understanding this.
Like
>> it's more than just sharing the Sabbath.
Yeah.
>> Or just sharing the state of the dead or
just sharing the truth on hellfire.
That's all of it. And I mean that's a
huge part of it. But helping to to
explain this as well.
>> There's a lot.
>> Yeah.
And so we need to be we need to be
praying as individuals. Say, "Lord, just
give me who I'm supposed to reach
>> and then help me to be able to share in
the way yep
>> that God wants us to share."
>> Yeah. All right, y'all. Give me 10 more
minutes. Can y'all do that? I know a lot
of you are going to work early tomorrow
morning.
>> I think I think they're fine.
>> Okay,
>> because y'all here is
>> they're very engaged.
>> Here [snorts] is where the rubber meets
the road, y'all. M
>> let let's let's go. We're we're almost
there. Matthew 15:7. And there was one
named Barabas which lay bound with them
that had made insurrection with him who
had committed murder in the
insurrection. So uh the Bible here is
telling us about this man named Barabus.
And we know that Barabus
uh ultimately is a representation
of [snorts] Satan himself.
>> He's a counterfeit Christ. Mhm.
>> Now, why did they choose Barabus over
Jesus?
>> They chose Barabus over Jesus because
Barabus was a nation man.
>> In other words, Barabus was an
insurrectionist.
>> Like, he was like, "Listen, man. It's
about overthrowing the government." They
chose Barabus because Barabus was a
nationalist.
>> Listen to me, y'all.
>> He was radical.
>> He was radical. He was a nationalist.
And it was about nation for Barabus.
Jesus wasn't like that. So they rejected
him. Now
>> Jesus was meek and humble.
>> That's right. So if Bar Abba Bar Abbus
means son of the father which it does
and when we put Jesus next to Barabus we
have a counterfeit of Jesus. Would it
not make sense that when the final bar
abbas comes [clears throat]
he will come as one who is here
>> to glorify
the nation.
H
please think y'all
please think this through. Mhm.
>> If Christian nationalism is all about
the idea that God has ordained America
and America is going to be God's heaven
on earth, would it not make sense that
when the ultimate bar Abbas comes, the
son of the father, that he is in essence
going to say yes, America is great. And
will that not lead the Christian world
to just absolutely lose their minds in
excitement?
>> In other words, this false messiah is
not going to lift up and glorify the
kingdom of heaven. He's going to lift up
and glorify
>> America.
>> And that's why America is the central
spot.
The second beast is the central spot
where the image is set up,
>> where this kingdom on earth is set up.
The antichrist is going to is going to
be a lover
>> of America.
>> And you know who's going to be drawn to
that? Everyone who idolizes America.
>> They're going to be like, "Look at
this."
>> Yeah. He may be doing crazy things and
saying crazy things and may be as
corrupt as ever, but you know what? He's
for America.
And that's all we need to hear.
Jesus
is an American.
American Jesus.
>> American Jesus.
>> Now, now hold on. Remember this y'all.
Remember this is exactly what happened
in the days of Christ. Come on, let's
read. Let's read. So when Jesus referred
to the blessings given to the Gentiles,
the fierce national pride of his hearers
was aroused and his words were drowned
in the tumult of voices. Can you imagine
cursing Jesus out because he was talking
about everybody's equal?
His
own people
have the spirit of rage in them when
Jesus says, "Hey, you know what? The
stranger, the immigrant, the the guy
that is not like you, that is not one of
you, he's God's childhood." Mhm.
>> Accustomed to looking upon themselves as
the only people favored of God, they
could not endure the thought that the
despised Gentiles should share the
privilege which had hitherto belonged to
them exclusively. National pride bore
down every argument which could
influence their reason or command their
reverence. An outburst of rage
interrupted his speech as all with one
voice cried out, "Away with this fellow
from the earth, for it is not fit that
he should live." And this is a reference
to Paul. Let's keep reading. Back to
Jesus. The moment he made reference to
the favors and blessings given to the
Gentiles, their national pride was once
was at once escalated. Words were spoken
in no gentle manner, and his words were
drowned in a tumult there in the
synagogue. They laid hands, violent
hands on Jesus, hurried him to the brow
of a hill where upon the where on the
city was built with the purpose of
casting him down headlong. But some were
seeking to counterwork their purposes.
Jesus stood in calm majesty while their
wrath seived around him and they
contended what should be done with him.
>> You guys, this is all the spirit of
national pride.
They were filled with self-sufficiency
and self-esteem, seeking constantly for
the supremacy, spurning everything that
did not bear the appearance of worldly
wisdom and national pride and religious
exclusiveness. His work was to correct
these evils and attract men to virtue,
to purity, to humility and to God to
devest religion of the narrow conceited
formalism which made it a rigorous
burden.
>> Turning to the Jews, we see the other
side. The scribes and Pharisees had
separated themselves from God by their
national pride.
They looked for the Messiah to come as a
temporal prince to exalt the Jewish
nation above all other nations on the
earth. As their self-confidence
increased, their dependence on God
decreased. So listen, if the Jews in
those days were looking for a messiah to
come who would exalt the Jewish nation
above all nations on the earth, what do
you think the counterfeit messiah when
he comes under the opaces of the second
beast of Bible prophecy? What do you
think he's going to do?
>> Wow.
>> I am here to let you know you Christians
that you've been right all along.
America is God's land.
>> And we are now here to set the record
straight.
[clears throat]
>> Wow. Yeah.
>> I will read two more and then we're
going to transition to one last point
and we're done.
>> Okay. The word of God as they professed
to believe stated plainly every detail
of his ministry. And again and again he
quoted from the prophets to declare this
day is a scripture fulfilled in your
ears. But their mind but the minds of
their of the Jewish people were so
concentrated on the hope of earthly
power and national elevation that they
despised the humble Nazarene and would
not have him reign over them. Again,
hatred of the Romans and national and
spiritual pride led the Jews still to
adhere rigorously to their own forms of
worship. We're just going to stop right
there.
>> They had studied the prophecies, but
without spiritual insight. Thus, they
overlooked those scriptures that pointed
to the humiliation of Christ's first
advent and misapplied those that speak
of his glory to the second coming. Pride
obscured their vision. They interpreted
prophecy in accordance with their
selfish desires.
>> Jesus knew that their hope of national
greatness would be disappointed for it
was based on a misinterpretation of
scripture. With deep earnestness, he
explained the prophecies and tried to
stir up the people to study God's word.
Now, here's what I need y'all to
understand.
The same thing
that led the Jews to reject Christ. It
was national pride. He didn't come to
deliver them from the Romans. He came to
deliver them from sin. No, no, no, no,
no, no, no.
>> We hate the Romans. And that's who we're
after.
>> Wow.
>> It is that same spirit in Christian
nationalism today, y'all.
>> It is the same thing.
>> Yeah.
>> And so many people are caught up in it.
Mhm.
>> And as we track this history, we see
this is exactly what's going on.
Now, I got to show you.
Here's a Sunday law. Are you ready?
>> Here we go. Here we go.
Ellen White writes, "Persecution ceased
and instead," she's talking about
Constantine's day, "and instead they
were substituted the dangerous
allurements of temporal prosperity and
worldly honor." idoltors were led to
receive a part of the Christian faith
while they rejected other essential
truths. They professed to accept Jesus
as the son of God and to believe in his
death and resurrection. But they had no
conviction of sin and felt no repentance
or a or a need for a change of heart.
With some concessions with some
concessions on their part, they proposed
that Christians should make concessions
that all might unite on the platform and
belief in Christ. So what
[clears throat] I want you to lock in on
lock in here is temporal prosperity.
Professed Christians of our time are
expecting the temporal prosperity of the
church in the conversion of the world
and the enjoyment of the temporal
millennium. What she's saying is
Christians of today are looking for
temporal that means earthly prosperity.
Watch
John [clears throat] and Andrews writes
this. The people of God indeed are
looking forward to the time when the
lamb who is the king of kings and lord
of lords shall reign in person over the
whole earth. But with the mass, this
view has given place to the more
congenial idea of a spiritual reign and
a temporal prosperity and triumph. This
view holds holds out to men the prospect
of peace and safety notwithstanding the
evidence has been spread out before them
that the hour of God's judgment has come
and that no better state of things can
exist till the curse shall be removed
from the earth. The warning respecting
the coming storm of wrath has been most
faithfully faithfully given, but by the
multitude it has been rejected, thus
leaving them to the deceptions that are
already coming upon the earth. They
dreamed that the earth
with all its progress and with all its
improvements is far too lovely and
excellent for God to destroy. Peace and
safety is the delusive dream in which
men indulge while the wrath of God hangs
over them.
She says this, "Has not the tempor the
Protestant church acted the part of the
false prophet?" Most I'm sorry, this is
still uh this is still um uh
JN Andrews. Still Jane Andrews. Has not
the Protestant church acted the part of
the false prophet most effectually and
promising of the to the world a thousand
years of peace and prosperity before the
day of wrath? She has prophesied this
out of her own own heart. For God has
never spoken the reverse of this. The
Protestant church as a body now
proclaims this doctrine as expressing
the great object for which they labor
temporal prosperity and triumph in a
world that has ever rejected Christ.
>> Now, why is this so significant?
We got five slides left, y'all. So, fear
not.
The temporal prosperity they're looking
for is in essence
will be the sign of the Sunday law.
>> Yes.
>> In other words, the Sunday law will
become the sign of national greatness.
>> Let me say it again, y'all.
The counterfeit Messiah will come
lifting up the nation.
>> His sign,
his sign
will be a sign of national greatness.
>> Here is my day.
>> This is my nation.
>> Right?
>> This is the Christian nation. He can't
he's not going to do that in in Iraq.
He's not going to do that in these other
He's going this is going to be the
basis.
>> This is a sign of national greatness.
>> This is a I am I am lifting up the
nation. See, you guys are right. This is
the nation.
>> And here is the day that symbolizes you
are down with this nation. You are one
of us.
>> And if you reject this day, you're not
an American.
>> If you reject this day, you're not a
believer. If you reject this great sign
of prosperity, which will be the sign of
of my kingdom now set up on earth over
the whole earth.
>> You're demonstrating that you're nothing
but a heathen.
>> And this
>> now go ahead.
>> I was going to say this is really where
the whirlwind comes in.
>> That's right.
>> Because
you like just saying that is not going
to bring everybody together. But with
the whirlwind and understanding,
>> so think about
>> the miracle that's going to be
happening.
>> The miracle that's going to happen.
>> That's what's going to bring everyone
together to basically worship.
>> The rest of the world is not worshiping
America.
>> I mean, take Sabbath and Sunday out, you
know, worship. They're not even put that
to the side. They're not worshiping or
caring about America. But bringing all
of that together,
>> this is the sign of greatness. Look at
the miracle. Mhm.
>> He's exalting our nation. This is
manifest destiny.
>> Mhm.
>> This is uh this is American
exceptionalism. This is what we've been
saying. God put us here for this reason.
>> And now beloved, you can begin to
understand that's why because the Sunday
law will be the sign of greatness of the
nation because what what is their
concern? It's not about the kingdom of
heaven.
>> It's about the kingdom of this world.
And so now remember, let me let me go
back to the screen here. Remember in
Nehemiah's day, the Bible says in
Nehemiah 13:17, "Then I contended with
the nobles of Judah, and said unto them,
what evil thing is this that you do and
profane the Sabbath day? Did not your
fathers thus? And did not our God bring
all this evil upon us and upon the city?
Yet you bring more wrath upon Israel by
profaining the Sabbath?" This same
principle will be repeated, y'all.
but with America instead of Israel.
>> It's going to be America and by
extension the whole world.
>> This is what the this this is what
brings it all together for us to
understand. There's a reason why Satan
is pushing this nationalism in America.
just like he did with Israel in in
Jesus's day. So he is doing now with the
Christians in America that they have
sold out mingled with the sons with the
with the seed of men
>> for prophetic uh for political gain
and ultimately the idol itself is
America. Mhm.
>> And when America as Babylon was the idol
in Gen in in Daniel 3, America is the
idol in Revelation chapter 13. But it is
an America that is God orained.
>> Worship.
>> Worship the beast.
>> Worship the beast because this is God's
will
>> for the world.
[clears throat]
It will be declared. Watch this. It will
be declared that men are offending God
by the violation of the Sunday Sabbath.
That this sin has brought calamities
which will not cease until Sunday
observance shall be strictly enforced.
And that those who pres who present the
claims of the fourth commandment, thus
destroying reverence for Sunday, are
troublers of the people, preventing
their restoration to divine favor and
temporal
prosperity.
>> That's nationalism right there.
>> Yeah.
You're preventing the greatness of this
nation, temporal prosperity, because you
refuse to honor the day of the Lord.
>> By a national act enforcing the false
Sabbath, they will give life and vigor
to the corrupt faith of Rome, reviving
her tyranny and oppressing and
oppression of conscience. Why is it
national? Why will it be a national
Sunday law?
>> Because it's Christian
>> nationalism.
This is for the good of the nation.
>> All right, let me hit these last slides,
you guys.
This is from last week. Two weeks ago,
we read and I'm going to show you
something to just tie this all in. Two
weeks ago, we read from Josiah Strong.
Josiah Strong was a man that lived
during the 1800s who was a strong pro he
was a minister and a strong proponent of
manifest destiny of um the Anglo-Saxon
>> uh you know racial supremacy um you know
against immigrants coming into the
country and I want I read from his book
last week but I want to read this
particular paragraph. Listen to this.
Moreover, immigration not only furnishes
the greater portion of our criminals, it
is also the morals of the native
population.
>> It is disease and not health which is
contagious. Most foreigners bring with
them continental ideas of the Sabbath
and is sadly manifest in all our cities
where it is being transformed from a
holiday from a holy day into a holiday.
That's pretty crazy.
It's those people out there that are not
of our faith that are bringing
moral decay into our nation
based upon
their
beliefs, based upon their lack of belief
in what we believe. And this is exactly
what Ellen White says when she says, "It
will be said that the morals of our
nation are falling because of a
desecration of the Sabbath,
>> meaning Sunday,
>> right?" So he was comparing Sunday.
>> That's right. He's talking about Sunday.
>> Sunday Sabbath. That's
>> right. He's talking about Sunday. And he
this listen now this
>> something that's new to some people that
they actually call Sunday Sabbath. So
this
>> so I mean it's sometimes it's new to
some Sabbath keepers to hear other
people say that. So I was just making
sure that you're understanding what
>> so here's a man who's saying listen
Josiah Strong go look him up.
>> Sabbath desecration is connected with
the morals of other races who are not as
superior as we are.
>> And you [clears throat] guys, Satan is
throwing all this into the mix. all of
this into the mix because he doesn't
really care what he uses.
>> He just needs to appeal to the carnal
heart.
That is the point.
>> He connects what he wants to happen to.
But it the way he connects to the carnal
heart is really pride. It was the first
that's what was the first sin that was
established in him.
>> Yes.
>> And that is where all of this can
connect to.
>> I'm still taking it back down to the
foundation of racism, which is just the
feeling that you're better than somebody
else.
>> Yep.
you puff yourself up.
>> And we need to understand, you guys.
Yeah, we need to understand, you know,
it's kind of weird how,
>> you know, we we know that Satan doesn't
back off of sins,
>> but for some reason, a lot of us think,
well, he backed off of racism.
>> Yeah. No,
>> that's not a thing anymore.
>> No, no, no.
>> Like the devil's like, you know,
>> that's his foundational racism. I always
said Satan was the first racist.
>> Like he was against the whole human race
and that's his whole point, right? How
can I get them to turn on one another?
>> Right. And so when we're like
>> make them feel that they're better than
each other.
>> Yeah. So when we're like, "Oh, racism is
not a thing anymore." It's literally
like saying, "Oh yeah, Satan gave up on
that sin. He doesn't push that anymore.
You know, we've got better. We We're not
like that anymore." No, y'all. No.
>> Just like every other sin is going to
increase to the end of time.
>> So So watch this. Watch this. Let's go
back to the screen.
Political corruption is destroying love
and just love of justice and regard for
truth. And even in free America, rulers
and legislators in order to secure
public favor will yield to the popular
demand for law enforcement Sunday
observance.
Public favor,
>> rulers and legislators
for their own political gain.
Satan is doing his best. I want y'all to
watch this. Mhm.
>> These are my last last slides here.
Satan is doing his best to block the way
to the progress of this message. He is
putting forth efforts to bring about the
enactment of of a Sunday law which will
result in slavery in the southern field
and will close the door to the
observance of the true Sabbath which God
has given to men to keep holy.
Ellen White said this in 1909.
Now, I'm sure y'all didn't hear this.
>> I'm sure that y'all didn't hear this.
>> In n This is This is not 1860.
>> This is not 1870.
in 1909.
And you're thinking, well, why are you
tying Sunday laws with, you know, racism
and and you guys listen to me?
>> In 1909,
Satan is doing his best to block the way
to the progress of the message. He is
putting forth efforts to bring about the
enactment of a Sunday law which will
result in slavery
in the southern field and will close the
door to the observance of the true
Sabbath which God has given to men to
keep holy. Why would she say that in
1909?
I close with this final statement. This
final statement is a conversation
between uh between Ellen White and PT
man. And listen to what she says here.
[cough and clears throat]
Church members and priests and rulers
will combine to organize secret
secret societies to work in their land
to whip, imprison, and destroy the lives
of the colored race. History will be
repeated. She wrote that in 1895.
She wrote that in 1895.
And then she writes this. I would not
advise that this be published in our
papers, but let the workers have it in
leaflets and let them keep their own
councils.
In 1895,
she is writing that history will be
repeated.
And she says she understands the
significance of what she's saying and
she literally says don't put this out
there. Let the workers have it but don't
put this out there.
Listen to P team again. Ellen White
says, "There will be slavery just as
verily as it had has been only upon a
basis that is more favorable and secure
to the white people." This is in 1907,
you guys. PT man responds to her. He
says, "More secure because they do not
have to feed the ne the negroes and care
for them. Then if the negro has got has
got outside the district or if he is
loafing and not working, they can put
him in the chain gang for a year." Ellen
White responds, "This is the danger.
That is why I have pleaded and intreated
intreated and intreated for the work to
be done in the South because I knew
I knew that this very race war would be
introduced."
You guys
>> what we see happening today
is not a coincidence.
>> It is not make believe. It is not
accidental.
What we see happening today.
Yeah. You can't tell me Ellen White was
not of God. You can't.
>> Yeah.
>> What we see happening today and what she
said was not a blanket statement.
Obviously,
>> you know, the Adventist church was made
up of people who were abolitionists. And
so, we're not talking we're not talking
blanketly. We're not saying, "Oh, the
whole thing at the end of time is about
this." But what I am saying
>> is that men are hungry for power in
multiple ways. politically, racially, in
so many different ways. And the devil at
the end of time is going to ball it all
up into one,
>> right?
>> And if we are not careful and paying
attention and watching what's going on,
what has happened in the past and what
is happening now, we will become blind
and susceptible and say, "Oh, the
devil's not doing anything." And only
when it is too late will you realize you
have been caught up.
And you're going to ask yourself, how
did I get here?
>> How did this happen? How did I not see
the writing on the wall?
>> You guys, you can go research all this
for yourself.
[clears throat]
>> Nicole has a good question, I think,
because she's our our friend and a
church member. [laughter]
>> So, she asked, "People of color or all
Sabbathke keepers will be enslaved." She
Ellen White literally says people of
color,
>> but she also says, I mean, is prophetic
that many people will be imprisoned,
>> right?
>> So, in in some cases, it's going to be
based on you're not following the laws
we've laid out. And in other cases, it's
just going to be pure racism. It's not a
it's not a blanket statement,
>> but it will it will involve these things
because these are the things of the
natural and unconverted heart.
>> It's not a big lift for America to do
something just purely on racism.
>> Look at the history. Look at why our
pioneers identify this power as
hypocritical
>> and then see what has happened
throughout this nation's history and see
the things that are happening today.
>> I was going to say
>> just look at what's happening today.
Look at look at look at the immigration
issue, right? We're not saying don't
have immigration law. I'm not saying
that. But I'm saying look at the spirit
behind so much that is going on today
and and people are becoming more open
and talking. I mean, I'm watching videos
now where it's like, wait, it's all
right to say that on on YouTube
>> that, you know, certain races of people
are just stupid and naturally don't have
what other races have. And and it's not.
You used to be embarrassed to say it, so
you say it secretly. And now people are
just saying it open. Christians.
>> Mhm.
And beloved, what I'm trying to tell
you,
>> what I'm trying to say
is that if we don't as a people stand up
>> and let our voices be heard and give a
warning
of of where this is going and how it's
all unfolding and and to understand that
this what you are seeing is nothing more
than corrupted Christianity. the
children of the sons of God mingling
with the children of men and that this
is an abomination to God.
>> If we don't stand up and speak, we will
be held accountable by God himself.
>> Yes.
>> Wow.
>> All right.
That was part two.
>> That was part two. that really brought
it that really brought it home. Um,
we have a lot of work we have a lot of
work to do. I mean, I'm still I'm still
stuck on that. And um,
yeah. Wow.
We have a lot of work to do. We have a
lot of work to do to share the truth.
>> Yeah. So we all need to study and to
know it like
we all need to study like you to be
honest.
>> Not putting we all just need to study.
We all need to study. But well, I mean,
I'm just saying like to be because I
mean, somebody was saying way probably
an hour ago, somebody was saying, "How
do I share this truth with with somebody
who's like, you know,
>> yeah,
>> in love with um
well, with the nation or just has like
such, you know, this is a hard this it's
a hard truth I to to to share in some
circles for sure. Um because I was
thinking like we're
I don't want to say uh well I'll just
say trained I mean and I don't want to
say indoctrinated either but you're
taught
love for country and I don't mean like
you can't appreciate living in America
and you know all the great things we
have going on here. I'm not saying that,
but loving country over
everything else. Like you even feel bad
to I know in some circles, as much as we
understand Revelation 13:11, some some
circles, you know, I'll be honest, like
even when you when pastors are
evangelists to evangelistic series, they
save that to the very last. And they're
so
>> the 10 horns.
>> No, not the ten horns. I'm talking about
um just exposing Revelation 13:11. like
what beast that is like it's such a
delicate thing and you know this is it's
just so delicate you know it's it's
>> it's like a golden calf
>> that right so I'm just saying like to
talk about this it's not easy unless
you're like number one close to God and
studying
>> and knowing it well
>> and it's important to study
>> it's important to study
>> right it's important to like get if
>> okay take take that three month period
that six month period and say I I need
to study this out so I can understand it
for you can share and feel comfortable.
>> Yeah.
>> Many times we don't share
[clears throat] um because we we're not
feeling confident and comfortable with
sharing. So, and that's what Satan
wants. He wants us not to study like
this because he doesn't want us to be
confident because then if we're not
confident, we'll be silent.
>> Yeah. Um and let me see this. Someone
was asking about the 10 horns in
Revelation chapter 17. Are they the
same? Are they the same? Um the 10 horns
in Revelation 17 are they go back to
Daniel chapter 7 [clears throat]
and they will culminate at the end of
time. So as I said in my previous study
the the 10 toes of Daniel 2 continue to
the end of time. So it's not 10 new toes
right at the end of time.
>> It's it's uh all the 10 horns.
The T horns will be symbolic of the
entire world at the end of time. It's
not just Europe. It will be the entire
world. When Jesus comes again, he's not
coming to destroy Europe. He's coming to
destroy the whole world. So when that
stone that is cut out without hands
destroys the image on the on the feet of
iron and clay, that represents the
entire world, not Europe. So this is
evidence that the t horns they start out
but they will grow to encompass the
whole world.
>> Okay.
Um you guys [clears throat] study study
study to show yourself approved and you
know uh an appeal.
We have to
understand that the devil is trying to
divert our attention with things that
are just so so off the the He's got us
locked in.
>> He's got us locked in on things. We're
ch we're chasing rabbits,
>> prophetic rabbits. Look at this here.
you know, [clears throat]
all the things that we've heard in the
last five years about what was
definitely going to be the cat the the
catalyst to bring this about.
And here we are.
>> Here we are. We need to understand that
the devil is is diverting our attention
to things that that are not important so
that we're not studying the things that
are important. Mhm.
>> And so I just want to appeal to you
guys. Please
stop eating junk food.
A lot of us are consuming junk food
instead of consuming the actual word of
God.
>> Let's focus on the word of God and stop
eating sugary junk food that we like to
call, you know, present truth or pre
whatever it is. Let's get into the word
of God. That is my appeal.
>> Put the junk food down.
>> Study for yourself to show yourself
approved.
>> And don't be distracted by things that
are not prophetic, that are mislications
of prophecy.
Stay locked in on the word of God.
>> Stay focused. Yeah. Amen. Amen.
[clears throat]
>> All right.
>> Yes. Wow. Thank you guys for thank you
for uh being here with us and doing this
Bible study with us. Um, I know many
people are going to go back and continue
to study and study and um, yes,
>> I will say this. If you want to support
uh, Living Man Ministry, I'm
>> Power of the Land Ministry, I'm sorry,
Power of the Land Ministry, please.
>> I'm going to put our Patreon link in the
chat. Um, make sure you get on Patreon.
And [clears throat] I haven't jumped on
in a in a in a couple of uh weeks to
talk about this, but the photo theology
Bible study suite,
>> yes, the slides will be up. You'll get
access to that on the Patreon site.
Okay.
>> Um but the photo theology Bible study
suite for those of you who support the
ministry uh financially through the
photo the I mean through Patreon,
>> you will get free access to
>> the Bible study suite. So, please be
aware of that. Um, a
burninghammergmail.com
and, uh, may God bless you guys.
>> We're gonna put it in the link. Right.
>> We're going to put it in the link, the
the link for Patreon.
>> Um, and, uh, on Patreon will be the link
for the slides. Okay.
>> Right.
>> So, again, may God bless you. And,
Atant, do you want to pray?
>> I'll pray. I will pray.
>> Heavenly Father, Lord, we thank you
[clears throat]
uh, for this study tonight. Another
eyeopening uh, Bible study. and
presentation. I pray that we will all
just take this so very seriously and
we'll just go deeper in our personal
Bible study so that we can become
confident uh and share this with the
world. And we ask these things in Jesus
name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> All right guys,
>> God bless you and uh until next time.